[ 웨스트우드 힐스 ]
[ 퇴역군인 병원 ]
긴장 푸세요, 그냥 주사에요.
NURSE:
Relax, it's just a shot.
러트넘, 러트넘, 진정해요.
Rutnam, Rutnam,
take it easy.
흥분하지 마세요.
Just calm down.
헤이, 아무도 안 해쳐요.
Hey, no one's
gonna hurt you.
아무도 안 해쳐요.
No one's gonna hurt you.
Okay, okay, okay, I'm cool.
알았어, 알았어, 알았어,
진정할께.
좋아요.
Okay.
(grunting)
Oh!
헤이!
GUARD:
Hey!
밖에선 조심해요, 알았죠?
Be safe out the, okay?
고마워요.
Thanks.
헤이, 이런 된장!
Hey! What the hell?
NCIS LA 6x22 ♪
Field of Fire
방송일: 2015년 4월 27일
NCIS: LA 6x22
Field of Fire
Original Air Date on April 27, 2015
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
번역 및 싱크 재조정: 비키남.
좋았어, 이거야.
완벽해. 내가 찾은 애야.
All right, this is it, this
is the perfect kid. I found him.
꽤 귀엽네.
He is pretty cute.
샘, 이거 봤어요?
Sam, you see that?
뭔데. 자네의 첫
증명사진인가, 딕스?
What's that, your first
mug shot, Deeks?
왜, 얘가 베게 파마하고
Oh, you mean
'cause he got styled
능글맞게 웃고 있어서요?
by pillow hair
and he's smirking?
그러고보니 날 좀 닮았네.
Actually, that does
kind of look like me.
딕스가 멘토링 프로그램에
참여했어요.
Deeks has signed up for
a mentoring program.
그거 훌륭하네.
Ah, that's
commendable.
제발...
Please.
매 주말엔 이 애랑
지내야 해요.
Yeah, I get to spend
every weekend with him.
감시장치를 써도 돼.
Yeah, you could use
the supervision.
얘 '좋아요'가 뭔지
함 들어 보세요:
Listen to his likes:
Surfing,
파도타기, 피쉬타코,
3연승 기다리기...
fish tacos--
and wait for the trifecta--
얼간이 삼총사.
그리고 '싫어요'는
규칙과 양말.
the Three Stooges. And his
dislikes are rules and socks.
내가 얘의 롤모델이 되려구요.
생활 바로잡기를 해 주려고 합니다.
And now I'm gonna be a role
model. I'm, like, start,
you know, shaping his life.
You're gonna shape his life?
자네가 걔 생활을
바로 잡는다고?
네.
Yeah.
So he'll be stuck in
걔를 영원히
사춘기에 묶어두려구?
perpetual adolescence.
No, you know, I think Deeks
내 생각엔 딕스가 걔한테
몇가지 가르칠게 있을거야.
actually has a few things
to teach this kid.
- 감솨요.
- 정말? 예를들면?
Thank you.
Really? Such as?
걔의 문화적 지평을
넓힌다든지.
Such as expanding
his cultural horizons.
그래, 맞아,
그랜드 세프트 오토 5
싫어할 애들은 없으니까.
Oh, yeah, what kid wouldn't want
to play Grand Theft Auto V
and pause reruns
of Baywatch?
베이왓치
되돌려가며 보기랑.
(everyone laughing)
You know what?
다들 날 놀리고 싶겠지만
난 아주 기쁘답니다.
You make fun all you want,
but I'm stoked.
And in all reality,
this is like, uh,
이건 현실적으로
마치 아빠되기 선행학습
같은 거라구요.
you know, it's like
a precursor to being a father.
- 뭐라구?
- 정말 시작이군.
SAM: What?
Well, there's a start.
워 워 워 워, 잠깐만.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
slow down, guys.
자네가 누굴
도우려는 건 좋아.
It's nice that
you're trying to help.
하지만 부모가 되는건
별개의 문제야.
But it's one thing
to talk about parenting--
actual parenting
is a totally different thing.
실제로 자식을 키운다는건
완전히 다른 얘기라구.
왜, 또 캠런이
휴대폰에 문제가 있대?
Kamran having some
cell phone problems again?
자넨 애들 키우는게
얼마나 힘든지 절대 모를거야.
You will never know how hard
it is to raise a child.
What makes you think I've
ruled out that possibility?
어째서 자넨
내가 그 가능성을
배제했다고 생각하나?
- 뭐라구요?
- 진짜에요?
What?
Seriously?
뭐가?
난 아직 젊다구.
What? I'm still
young enough.
조엘과 나는 이제
정상궤도에 들어섰다구.
Joelle and I have got
things back on track.
어떻게 될지 누가 알아?
Y-You know...
You never know.
- 작은 소문자 g 가 막 돌아다녀?
- ㅋㅋㅋㅋ
(chuckles) Little
lowercase Gs running around?
Look, if you're gonna do it,
take your time, start slow.
그렇게 하려거든
서둘지 말고 천천히 시작해.
Uh-huh. How so?
그래? 어떻게?
식물을 키워. 그게 살면,
애완동물을 키워.
Get a plant.
If that lives, get a pet.
중추신경계가
없는 놈으로.
One without a central
nervous system,
해파리 같은거.
like a jellyfish.
- 해파리라고?
- 해파리.
A jellyfish?
A jellyfish.
어, 알겠어.
Uh, okay.
여러분!
(whistle blows)
ERIC: Guys.
사건이에요.
오시죠, 지금.
We have a case.
Let's go. Now.
63명을 사살한 특무상사
코너 러트넘 입니다.
NELL: With 63 confirmed kills,
Gunnery Sergeant Connor Rutnam
아프간과 이라크에서
뛰어난 재능과 능률을 보인
was one of the most
talented and efficient
Marine Corps snipers
in Afghanistan and Iraq.
해병대 저격수 중
한명이었습니다.
그는 4번의 해외파병후
은퇴했는데,
He retired after
his fourth tour and later
그 후 정신적 퇴보 현상을
보이기 시작했습니다.
began showing signs
of psychological deterioration.
PTSD.
(외상 후 심리적 장애)
M40A5를 쥐고 있군요.
He's holding
an M40A5.
엄폐 상태로
장거리 목표물을
Used for long-range
precision fire on targets
정밀사격 하기 위한
저격용 소총입니다.
in a concealed position.
보통 지붕위에서
적 전투원이나 차량,
Often rooftops,
targeting anything
자살 폭탄범등
뭐든 저격합니다.
from enemy combatants
to suicide bombers.
여자나 아이들도
예외는 아니죠.
Which could include
women and children.
러트넘군이 집으로 돌아와
일상 생활에 적응하는데
HETTY: It became clear
that Mr. Rutnam
어려움을 겪고 있었다는게
was struggling
with adjusting
확실해 졌지.
to life at home.
어제까지 그는 퇴역군인 병원에서
치료를 받고 있었다네.
Until yesterday, he was
receiving treatment at the VA.
간호사와 위생병이
그를 제지하려 했지만
ERIC: A nurse and an orderly
were trying to restrain him
when he overpowered them
and escaped the facility.
그는 제지를 뿌리치고
병원을 탈출했지.
정신적으로 불안정한
매우 숙련된 저격수가
So we have a mentally unstable,
highly-skilled sniper
도망중인 거군요.
on the loose.
With the presence
위생병의 유니폼과 뱃지를
훔칠 정도로 침착해.
of mind to steal the orderly's
uniform and badge.
그가 훨씬
위험하단 얘기군요.
Which makes him
all the more dangerous.
그를 뚜껑 열리게
할만한게 있나요?
Anything specific set him off?
HETTY: Not that
we could tell.
우리가 아는 한 없네.
Mr. Hanna, Mr. Callen,
해나군, 캘런군.
병원 사람들을 만나
얘기해 보게.
talk to the people
at the VA.
그의 상태에 관해 무슨
주목할 만한게 있는지.
See if they can shine
any light on his condition,
혹은 행방에 대해.
uh, or whereabouts.
- 갑시다.
- 오케이.
Let's do it.
Okay.
그는 또한 아내와
15살 된 딸이
He also has a wife
and 15-year-old daughter
베벌리우드에
살고 있습니다.
living in Beverlywood.
자네와 블라이양
둘이 가서 만나보게.
Whom you and Ms. Blye
are going to visit.
- 예스 맴.
- 넵.
Yes, ma'am.
On it.
그는 치료 과정에
DOCTOR:
He was responding well
순응을 잘 했었습니다.
to the course
of treatment:
약도 잘먹고, 1:1 이나
그룹 상담도 잘 받았죠.
meds, counseling--
both one-on-one and group.
언제부터 그가
악화되기 시작했죠?
When did he start
going south again?
- 약 2주 전부터요.
- 무슨 촉발요인이 있나요?
About two weeks ago.
Did something trigger it?
말씀드릴 만한게 없어요.
그게 참 모순적이거든요.
Not that we could tell.
That's the paradox.
환자의 상태가
악화되기 시작하면
When a patient's condition
starts to worsen,
환자로 하여금 자기 상태에 대해
말하도록 하는게 제일 힘들기 때문이죠.
the hardest thing is to
get them to talk about it.
Any person
그가 밖에나가 누군가 혹은
어딘가를 가 보고 싶어했나요?
or place he wanted to see
on the outside?
제가 아는한 없어요.
Not that I'm aware of.
어쩌면 그가 치료 받는 중
뭔가 얘기 했을지도 몰라요.
He might have said something
in his therapy sessions,
하지만 그건
공개를 못해 드립니다.
but those are off the record.
저는 당신이
우리가 처한 상황이
CALLEN:
Well, I'm sure you realize
the situation
we're dealing with.
어떤건지 잘
알고있을거라 믿습니다.
I do.
압니다.
코너는 심각한
감정적 문제를 갖고있는
Connor is a trained sniper
훈련된 저격수입니다.
with serious emotional problems.
사방에 총이 널린
도시에서 말이죠.
SAM: In a city full of
easy to access guns.
I don't write the rules,
gentlemen.
저는 규칙을 만들지
않습니다, 여러분.
저는 그저 여기서 여러 나쁜 상황들을
좋게 만들려고 노력하는 중일 뿐입니다.
I'm just trying to make the best
of a lot of bad situations here.
We understand.
알겠습니다.
마이크 타카하모를
한번 만나 보시죠.
You might want to speak
with Mike Takahamo.
He was Connor's attending
nurse when he escaped.
코너가 탈출했을때
그의 간호사를 했던 사람입니다.
죄송합니다.
이것들을 냉장고에 좀 넣구요.
Sorry, I just want to
get these in the fridge.
천천히 하세요.
Take your time, please.
남편분이 병원을 떠난 후
무슨 연락이라도
Have you heard anything
from your husband
since he left the VA?
온 거 없나요?
헤이 엄마!
밖에 차가 두대 있어!
GIRL (in distance):
Hey, Mom! Two cars outside!
우리 딸한테 아직
아무 얘기도 안했어요.
(door opens, closes)
I haven't told our daughter yet.
그가 파병됐을때 두분 모두
힘드셨을거라 믿습니다.
DEEKS: I'm sure it must
have been hard on you both
when he was deployed.
그리고 그가
집으로 돌아오면...
Then he comes home, and...
처음엔... 그렇게
나쁜것 같지 않았어요.
It just didn't seem
that bad at first.
그는 예전의
그가 아니었죠.
I mean, he wasn't himself,
하지만 한동안 그가
여기 없었기 때문에 어찌보면...
like he wasn't quite here,
but that's...
당연한 일이거니 했어요.
to be expected.
But then he started
acting strange.
그런데 그가 이상하게
행동하기 시작했습니다.
엄마말은 마치,
구속복을 입혀놓은
She actually means,
like, straightjacket
미치광이
같았다는 거죠.
cray cray.
저사람들 누구죠?
Who are they?
우린 네 아빠와
함께 일한단다.
We work with your dad.
여자 해병이군요.
Lady Marine.
이제 캘리포니아에서
Must be exciting
결혼할 수 있게되서
신나시겠네요.
(레즈비언이라고 놀리는 중)
you can finally get married
in California now.
Lisa!
리사!
왜요?
What?
해병 치고는
꼬질꼬질하네요.
Pretty scruffy
for a jarhead.
새 스타일이야..
It's a new look.
밀레니엄 세대를
모집하는 중이거든.
We're trying to
recruit millennials.
#꼬질꼬질
#scruffy.
잘났네요.
Whatever.
엄마 콜라 까먹었어.
You forgot to get Diet Coke.
사과드립니다.
(sighs) I apologize.
아니, 괜찮아요.
KENSI:
Oh, no need to.
- 우리 모두 사춘기 시절이 있었죠.
- 전 아직도요.
We've all been 15 once.
Still am.
따님은 최근에
어려운일을 많이 겪어서
She's been through
a lot recently,
so we totally understand.
충분히 이해합니다.
걘 아빠가 해외파병
가기 전에도
She wasn't the easiest
to deal with
다루기 힘든 얘였는데
before he went overseas,
아빠가 아프면서
and things just got worse
더 심해졌어요.
when Connor got sick.
하는 짓이...
Just attitude...
밤 늦게까지 안들어오고...
staying out late and...
얘가 그냥 화만 내고
You know, I can tell
that she's upset,
왜그러는지 도통
얘기를 안해요.
but she doesn't want
to talk about it.
지난번 우리가 병원으로
아빠 병문안을 갔을땐
The last time that we went
to visit him in the hospital
아빠가 좋아진 걸 보고
and she could see
he was getting better,
아빠랑 포옹도 했어요.
he hugged her.
전 걔가 10살 이후로
우는 걸 못봤어요.
I don't think I'd seen her cry
since she was ten.
그가 사라진지
겨우 몇시간 안됐지만
Well, he's only been
gone a few hours,
우리는 최선을 다해
그를 찾고 있습니다.
and we are using all of our
resources to find him.
정말입니다.
Absolutely,
만일 그에게서
연락이 오면
and please,
if he contacts you,
꼭 저희에게
알려주세요.
let us know.
Uh, we also need
Connor's computer.
아, 그리고 코너의 컴퓨터를
좀 가져가야 겠습니다.
제가 가져다 드릴께요.
I'll go get it.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
이 방이
그의 방이었습니다.
This was his room.
여기서 당신과 위생병을
공격했나요?
This is where he attacked you
and the orderly?
- 네 그렇습니다.
- 전부 얘기해 보실래요?
That's right.
You want to talk us through it?
I wrote it all in my report.
보고서에 모두 썼습니다.
You mind
saving us a read?
읽어볼 시간이 없어서 그러니
The Cliff Notes will be fine.
간단한 요약 만이라도...
환자는 혼란과 적개심의
징후가 보였습니다.
Patient showed signs
of confusion and hostility.
우리는 그를 제압하고
We attempted to restrain
진정시키려 했습니다.
and sedate him.
환자가 힘으로 위생병과
Patient physically attacked
the orderly
저를 공격했습니다.
그게 전부입니다.
and myself... end of story.
Now, if you'll excuse me...
전 이만 실례를...
Actually, we have
a few more questions.
아직 질문할게
남았습니다.
전 아는걸 모두
말씀드렸습니다.
I told you
everything I know.
저한테 뭘 더
원하시죠?
What more
do you want from me?
우선 좀더 친절한 태도와
사라진 환자에 대한 걱정부터
You know, a better attitude,
concern for a missing patient,
that would be a good start.
해 주셨으면 좋겠군요.
네 물론 걱정합니다.
Yeah, well, I am concerned.
제 간호를 기다리고 있는
Just as I am
for the other patients
다른 환자들과
똑 같이 말입니다.
that still that need attending.
됐나요?
Okay?
됐어요.
Okay.
와우,
Wow.
잠을 잘못 잤나,
꽤나 신경질적이군.
Somebody woke up on the
wrong side of the gurney.
Stressful job.
스트레스 받는
직업이잖아.
그것 말고 뭔가 더
있는 것 같아.
I'm sensing something
more than stress.
Insightful.
예리한데?
Maybe we ought
여기서 일 해 보는게 어때?
to put you to work here.
벌써 하고 있지.
자네도 해 보지그래?
Already am.
Maybe you should do the same.
Uh-huh.
G.
우선은 도로 침대 밑에
넣어두는게 좋을것 같네.
I think maybe we keep these
under the mattress for now.
NELL:
So the e-mails
코너의 컴퓨터로부터 빼낸
이메일들 속에는
we pulled
off Connor's computer
그가 갔을만한 곳에 대한
정보가 없습니다.
don't point to anyone
in particular he'd run to.
DEEKS: What about
his browsing history?
사이트 방문기록도 봤나?
Yes, there is a Web site
네, 그가 수도없이 방문했던
he paid numerous visits to.
웹사이트가 있습니다.
He watched this video
그가 병원에 들어가기 전에
이 비디오를
열번도 더 봤습니다.
a dozen times
before entering the hospital.
1966년 찰스 휘트먼.
(gunfire, people screaming)
KELSEY: 1966. Charles Whitman.
전 해병대 1급사수.
A former
Marine Corps sharpshooter.
텍사스 주립대 탑 꼭대기
Barricaded himself
on the 28th floor
observation deck
28층 관망대에
of the University
of Texas Tower
바리케이드를 치고서
with his Remington
700 Deer Rifle.
레밍턴 700 사슴사냥 총으로
(sighs)
26명의 학생을 부상입히고
Wounded 26 students.
15명을 죽였었죠.
Killed 15.
방금 노드호프에있는 고장난
교통 카메라를 하나 발견했는데
NELL: We just discovered
an out-of-service traffic cam
on Nordhoff.
렌즈에 금이가서
화면이 잘 안보입니다.
Now, the lens is cracked
and the view is limited.
증거자료로 쓰긴 부적당하지만
우리에게 도움은 줄 수 있습니다.
Making it unsuitable for the courts
but helpful to us.
이것은 코너 러트넘이
간호사와 위생병을
Right. This is 15 minutes
after Connor Rutnam
공격한지 15분 후의
모습입니다.
attacked the nurse
and orderly.
누군가 그의 계획을 알았군.
SAM:
Someone knew his plan.
그 차를 좀 더
확대해 줄 수 있겠나?
Can you zoom in any closer
on that car?
벌써 해 봤는데
별 도움이 안돼요.
We tried-- it doesn't help.
ERIC:
We can only make out that it's
화면으로부터 알아낸건
차가 토요타 캠리이고
a Toyota Camry,
mid-2000's most likely.
2000년대 중반 모델
인 것 같다는 정돕니다.
What about that homeless guy?
저기 부랑자쪽은?
음, 그의 쇼핑카트는
알버트슨 것이고
Mm, I'd say his cart's
an Albertson's,
세이프웨이사
최신 모델 같습니다.
possibly late-model Safeway.
이번주 내내 여기
불러다 놔야 겠군요.
He'll be here all week, folks.
ERIC:
He seems to be
그는 저 길에 매일
나타나는 것 같습니다.
a regular on
that street.
이건 지난 4일간 입니다.
This is the last
four days.
멀리서 찍힌거라
그한테서 뭐 별로
It's a long shot
he's gonna be able
알아낼게 없구만.
to give us anything.
그의 시야각이
카메라보다 더 넓지.
His field of vision
is wider than that camera.
포커스 조정을 못하잖아.
I don't know how
focused his lens is.
저 카트는 베브모 술상점것 같아!
확인해 봐.
That cart looks like
a BevMo! checkout.
ERIC: The car
was waiting there
차는 저기에 10분에서
15분 가량 서 있었어요.
a good ten, 15 minutes--
maybe he saw the driver.
어쩌면 그가 운전자를 봤겠군.
Well, it's worth a shot.
잘 봤네.
Thanks.
고마워.
I understand there's
been a turn of events
코너 러트넘 사건에
사태변화가 있었다고
들었습니다.
in the Connor
Rutnam case.
Indeed there has.
그래, 그랬다네.
캘런군과 해나군이
Mr. Callen and Mr. Hanna
그의 침대 밑에서
알수 없는 약이 든
found a baggie
of unidentified pills
비닐 백을 발견했지.
under his mattress.
지금 분석 중이라오.
It's being analyzed
right now.
그 병원에서 조제받은 약은
아닐 것 같네요.
Well, I doubt the VA's
dispensing meds in plastic bags.
Do you think
this could be the cause
그것 때문에
러트넘이 최근 문제를
일으킨 것 같나요?
of Rutnam's latest troubles?
It's possible.
가능성이 있네. 문제는,
누가 그에게 그걸 줬느냐는거지.
The question is,
who gave them to him?
Visitor?
방문객이?
병원 직원이?
Member of the staff?
아시다시피, 그 병원은
지금 정치적 입지가
I don't have to remind you of
the tenuous political situation
매우 불안합니다.
at the VA right now.
사실,
Actually,
우리가 그 약점을
좀 이용해 볼까 하네.
I was thinking that we
could use that to our advantage.
It would be
우리가 그곳에 감사 감독관을
위장 파견하면
unlikely to arouse any suspicion
if they received a visit from
an oversight compliance officer.
의심을 받지 않을 수
있을 것 같네.
Who would naturally be granted
access to all files and staff.
자연스럽게 모든 파일과
직원들에게 접근할 수 있겠군요.
I think Mr. Deeks cleans up
rather well, don't you?
내 생각엔 딕스군이 청소를
더 잘하는 것 같은데, 안그런가?
Depends on one's standards,
I suppose,
그야 기준의 문제겠죠.
하지만 뭘 하시려는지는
알겠네요.
but I get where you're going.
방문객쪽은 어떨까요?
What about on the visitor side?
블라이양은
저격수 출신이라
Ms. Blye's sniper background
아주 믿을만한
환자가 되 줄거네.
should make
for a very believable patient.
That's what concerns me.
바로 그점이 걱정입니다.
우린 아프간에서 아주
멀리 떨어져 있다오, 오웬.
We're a long way
from Afghanistan, Owen.
그러길 바라지요.
I hope so.
MAN (on TV):
In 1988, physicist Bob Lazar
told friends
he'd seen flying saucers
when he was working
on a top secret project
(coughs)
at Area 51.
Hey.
방금 여기 왔소?
You just get here?
예.
Yeah.
어느 병과요?
What branch?
해병. 당신은?
Marines. You?
유격대라오.
Rangers.
날 세워놓고
'꼼짝마' 하진 말아요.
Don't hold it against me.
(chuckles)
(TV show continues indistinctly)
그래 좀 어떤가요?
So how you doing?
보시다시피,
꿈같은 삶을 살고 있죠.
Living the dream, obviously.
Mm.
누굴 기다리나요?
You looking for someone?
네, 군에 같이 복무했던,
듣기로는 그가...
Yeah. A guy I served with,
I heard he, uh...
- 여기 있었다던데.
- 오, 이름이 뭐죠?
he was here.
Oh. What's his name?
러트넘.
Rutnam.
코너 러트넘.
그를 아나요?
Connor Rutnam. You know him?
Yeah.
네, 그런데 그는
이제 여기 없어요.
He's not here anymore.
Got released?
퇴원했나요?
아니, 그는 어제
무단이탈을 했어요.
No. He went AWOL yesterday.
Are you serious?
정말이에요?
Where'd he go?
어디로 갔나요?
No idea.
몰라요.
You a sniper
당신도 그와 같은
저격수인가요?
like him?
여군 전투팀, 네.
Female Engagement Team, yeah.
Connor used to talk about it.
코너가 간혹
그러더군요.
Killing somebody
from a distance...
멀리서 사람을
죽이게 되면...
didn't feel real.
실제란 느낌이
안든다고.
Until... it did.
나중에서야
들게 된다고...
Is that why you're here?
당신도 그래서
여기 오게 된건가요?
I don't really want
to talk about it.
별로 말하고 싶지
않네요.
Sorry.
미안해요.
Wonder why Connor left
like that, huh?
코너가 왜 그런식으로
떠났을까요?
I don't know.
He was doing fine,
모르죠.
잘 하고 있었는데.
then he
just started losing it
지난 몇주전 갑자기
이상해지기 시작했어요.
over the past few weeks.
Huh.
PTSD.
그가 어디갔는지
다른 사람한테
얘기하진 않았을까요?
Think he told anybody
where he was going?
I don't know--
he had a couple of visitors.
몰라요.
방문객이 두어명 있었는데
그 중 하나가 꽤 많은 시간을
같이 보내곤 했어요.
And there was this one guy
he spent a lot of time with.
직원에게 그의 이름을
말 하셨어야죠.
Well, you should tell
the staff his name.
I...
have no idea what it was.
이름을... 몰라요.
(man clears throat in distance)
즐거웠어요..
Nice talking to you.
이런, 젠...
Oh, my G...
미안, 미안해요.
Sorry, sorry.
코너한테 방문객이
좀 있었는데
(quietly):
Connor had several visitors.
He was tight with one.
그중 한명과 친했대.
Mm-hmm. Thank you.
감사해요.
(sighs)
Sorry.
미안해요.
아니, 괜찮아요.
No, it's fine.
우린 여기서
준수사항 감사를 받았습니다.
DR. RIVERS: We had
a compliance meeting here
three weeks ago.
3주 전에요.
전부 다 확인했죠.
Everything checked out.
확인 했다구요?
Checked out?
그럼 불안하고
위험한 환자가
So you would consider the escape
병원을 탈출한게
정상 업무의 일환이란
of a disturbed
and dangerous patient
말인가요?
as business as usual?
글쎄, 제가 보기엔
'Cause I would argue,
Dr. Rivers,
이곳 직원들만
'확인'한 것 같은데요,
the only thing
"checked out" here
리버스 박사님?
is your staff,
이제부터 제가 다시
제대로 '확인'하려고 합니다.
who I will now be
thoroughly "checking out""
We have nothing to hide here,
Mr. Rogers.
저희는 숨길게 없습니다, 로저스씨.
You will have complete
and unfettered access
누구하고든지
완전하고 자유롭게
얘기하실 수 있도록
조치해 드리겠습니다.
to anyone you wish
to speak with.
또한 모든사람들의
인사 기록이 필요합니다.
I'm also gonna need files
and records on everybody.
Fine.
좋습니다.
모든 계정의 비번과
접근허가를
I'll have all passwords
and authorizations
made available to you.
내 드리도록
하겠습니다.
I'm sorry,
is there a problem, Doctor?
혹시, 무슨 문제라도
있나요, 박사님?
제 문제가 뭔지
아시잖아요, 로저스씨?
You know what my problem is,
Mr. Rogers?
No, but I instinctually feel
like you're going to tell me.
아뇨, 하지만 직감적으로
당신이 말해 줄거라는 생각이 드네요.
100 patients
with mood disorders,
100명의 환자가
감정조절 장애,
외상후 스트레스,
post-traumatic stress
disorders,
약물 남용 장애,
조울증 등에
substance abuse disorders,
bipolar disorders,
시달리고 있습니다.
to name but a few.
시간도 없고,
Not enough time,
돈도 부족하고,
침대도 부족하고,
not enough money,
not enough beds,
직원도 부족한데
당신까지 왔어요.
not enough staff,
and now, you.
죄송하긴 한데, 전 단지
제 일을 하는 것 뿐입니다.
I'm sorry, Doctor,
I'm just trying to do my job.
물론 그러시겠죠.
Yes, you are.
방문자 기록도 필요합니다.
I'm also gonna need
the visitors log.
많은 사람들이
아이들 갖기를 원하는데
Lots of people are in love
with the idea of having kids,
그게 얼마나 힘든 일인지
아는 사람은 별로 없어.
but most have no idea what
they're getting into.
자네 부부 얘기야?
Did you and Michelle?
내말은, 우리도
그렇게 생각 했다구.
I mean,
we thought we did.
Read books,
we took classes...
책도 읽고
수업도 듣고...
That help?
그게 도움이 돼?
Hell, no.
(laughs)
젠장, 아니.
(Sam laughs)
안녕하세요?
How you doing?
실례합니다.
Excuse me.
뭐 좀 여줘보려구요.
Just want to ask you
some questions.
'사막의 폭풍'작전에
참전하신 모양이군요.
I'm gonna guess Desert Storm.
저는 '자유'작전에
참전 했습니다.
during Freedom for me.
또 다른 참전용사를
찾고있는 중입니다.
We're looking for another vet.
오늘아침 병원에서
도망쳐 나와
Took off from the hospital
this morning.
He bumped your cart.
당신 카트와
부딪힌 사람.
He might be in danger.
그가 위험에
처했을지도 모릅니다.
저쪽에서 차에 올라탔죠.
Got into a car right over there.
Gray Camry, '93.
93년식 회색 캠리.
덮개에 은색 페인트 칠했고.
Paint on the hood oxidized.
오른쪽 범퍼에
흰색 흠집이 있는데
White scratches on
the right front bumper,
벽에 부딪힌 것 같소.
probably hit a wall.
Replacement tires,
타이어는 교체한거,
짝퉁 미쉘린으로.
Michelin knockoffs.
You a mechanic?
차 수리공이세요?
Six years.
6년간.
제12 공병 대대.
12th Engineer Battalion.
혹시 번호판은
보셨나요?
Didn't happen
to get a plate, did you?
3, Delta,
Three, Delta,
Hotel, India...
(groans)
아주 잘하셨습니다.
You're doing great.
SAM:
What about the driver?
운전자는 요,
운전자를 보셨나요?
You see the driver?
Asian guy,
동양 사람.
파키스탄 아니면 인도 사람.
like Pakistani or Indian.
30, maybe.
나이는 한 30쯤.
이젠 가야겠소.
Look, I got to go.
Appreciate it.
감사 드립니다.
Hey, hey, hey.
저기 저기 저기요.
잠깐 잠깐 잠깐만요.
One sec, one sec, one sec.
대체 여기서
뭘 하고 계신거죠?
What the hell
are you doing out here?
그들을 못 믿어서
이러시는 건가요?
You don't trust them,
is that it?
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하쇼?
엉망이 됐죠.
They screwed up.
하지만 전부
나쁜건 아니에요.
It's not all bad.
제가 돌아 왔을땐
절 도와 줬어요.
They helped me when I got back.
기술도 있으시잖아요.
You got skills, man.
이 근처 어느 샵을 가도
Any shop around here
기꺼이 반겨 줄겁니다.
would be lucky to have you.
기운 좀 내시고
몸만 추스리시면 되겠네요.
You just got to get
your act together.
마음만 먹으면 됩니다.
It's your choice.
괜찮은겨?
You all right?
우린 군인들을 전쟁터에 보내
그들이 더 강인해지길 바라지.
We send guys to war,
expect them to step up.
하지만 그들이 심신이
모두 망가져 돌아오면
Then when they come
back all broken,
we step away.
우린 모른척 하지.
방해해서 죄송합니다,
리버스 박사님.
Sorry to interrupt,
Dr. Rivers.
무슨 문제라도 생겼나요,
로저스씨?
Trouble in the neighborhood,
Mr. Rogers?
Who has access to the meds,
the controlled pharmaceuticals?
누가 규제 약품들을
관리하죠?
Myself.
저하고,
모든 의사들, 그리고
일부 간호사들.
All of the doctors,
some of the nurses.
간호사 타카하모는요?
Nurse Takahamo?
He does.
예, 그도 합니다.
Nurse Takahamo...?
타카하모 간호사?
간호사!, 안돼!
Nurse, no!
(indistinct conversation)
헤이!
DEEKS:
Hey!
NCIS 다.
NCIS.
(panting)
게임 끝났어.
The game is up.
분명히 말 하겠는데,
And just for the record,
next time, never run.
다음번엔 절대 뛰지 마.
왜 뛰었나요?
DEEKS:
Why'd you run?
I like to keep in shape.
건강 유지를 위해.
모든 연방 교도소엔
달리기 트랙이 있으니
Well, every federal prison
has a running track.
가서 싫컷 하시지.
I'm sure you'll utilize that.
코너 러트넘의 침대 밑에서
금지 약물이 발견됐어.
We found unauthorized pills
in Connor Rutnam's bed.
We also found
inventory discrepancies
약품 보관소에 있던
일부 약들이
없어졌더구만.
with the meds
in lockup.
자네가 관리하는 약.
Meds that you had access to.
다른 사람들도
관리합니다.
Lots of people have access.
내 그럴줄 알고
DEEKS: You're absolutely
right, which is why
모든 의사와 간호사들의
we looked at every
single discrepancy
의약품 관리기록을
싹 다 조사해봤지.
to figure out which doctors
and nurses were working.
자넨 안빠지고 꼬박꼬박
거기서 일 했더구만.
You were working
every single time.
You are the common denominator.
자넨 공통 분모야.
그의 침대 밑에서
대체 뭘 발겼했죠?
What did you find under his bed?
그렇게 함
놀아보고 싶나?
Is this how you want to play it?
제 집을
뒤져볼건가요?
You going to search my place?
아니, 자네 양심에
함 맞겨 볼꺼야.
No, we're gonna use
the honor system.
DEEKS:
You know Connor Rutnam
알다시피 코너 러트넘은
저격수 였네.
was a sniper.
군에서 최고 중
한명이었지.
You know he was one of
the best in the service.
만약 그가 누구라도
쏘게 된다면
Anyone he decides
to put in his sights,
자넨 그의
공범이 되는거야.
you're gonna be
accessory to murder.
I didn't give Rutnam
any unauthorized meds.
전 러트넘에게 어떤 금지약물도
주지 않았습니다.
그럼 약품함에 있던
그 약들은
So those pills
from the lockup,
they just magically evaporated?
모두 증발이라도 했나?
No. I...
아니요...
- 제가 가져갔습니다.
- 와우.
I took them.
KENSI: Wow.
이젠 우리가
뺑뺑이를 돌고 있구만.
Now we're just moving
around in circles.
팔려고 가져간거에요,
환자한테 준게 아니고.
I took them to sell,
but not to patients.
그들에겐 별 의미가 없죠.
There'd be no point.
Half of them are already
getting oxy for free.
어차피 환자의 반은
무료 산소호흡을 받고 있어요.
게다가 환자들은
현찰 소유금지입니다.
Besides, the patients
aren't allowed to have cash.
그니까 자네말은,
So what you're saying is that
자네가 슬쩍한 약을
길거리에 내다 팔려고
했다는거야?
you were dealing the pills
you lifted on the street?
솔직히
말씀드린 겁니다.
I'm being honest here.
이제 절 좀
봐주시는거죠?
That's gotta count
for something.
You're being
honest because
자네가
궁지에 몰려서
your ass is being
nailed to the wall.
할 수 없이
한 얘기잖아.
그러니 어떻게
그 약이
DEEKS: So explain to me
how the pills
침대 밑에서 나왔는지
설명해 봐.
got underneath the mattress?
누군가가 그 약을
사 들여왔을 수 있죠.
Anyone could have
brought them in.
방문객은 검색을
안하거든요.
We don't search visitors.
코너는 꽤 많은 약을
갖고 있었어.
KENSI:
Well, Connor had several.
그가 유난히
더 많은 시간을
There was one in particular
that he spent more time with.
함께 보낸
사람이 있었지.
Do you remember?
기억하나?
Yeah.
네.
He started coming by
the past few weeks.
그가 몇주 전부터
병문안 오기 시작 했어요.
코너는 그 직후
빠져들기 시작했죠.
Connor started
sliding soon after.
이름을 아나?
You got a name?
마크.
Mark.
마크 시몬스.
Mark Simmons.
이 사람은 퇴역 육군 상병
마크 시몬스입니다.
This is former
Army Corporal Mark Simmons.
그는 지난 3주 동안
He visited Connor Rutnam
at the VA
코너 러트넘을
4번 방문했습니다.
four times
over the past three weeks.
둘이 한 나라에
있었던 적이 있나?
Did they cross paths
in-country?
Mmm, briefly,
in Afghanistan.
아프간에서
잠깐이요.
하지만 둘이 직접
만났다는 기록은 없습니다.
But records don't show
any contact with Connor
병원에서 만나기
전에는요.
until the VA visits.
하지만 둘 사이엔 좀 다른
뭔가가 있습니다.
But they do show a
little something else.
(clears throat)
시몬스는 6개월전
전역했습니다.
ERIC: Simmons was discharged
six months ago.
그리고는 바로
PFA에 가입을 했죠.
And shortly after,
he joined the PFA--
"자유 미국의 수호자들"
Protectors of a Free America.
프레드 킹톤에의해
1987년 설립 됐습니다.
It was founded by
Fred Kington, 1987.
극우 조직이군.
A right-wing extremist
organization.
깃발 뒤에 숨어서
Hiding behind the flag.
모든 회교도들을 끌어모아
They want to round up
every Muslim
미국 밖으로
실어 나르려 했지.
and ship them out of the U.S.
Someone with Connor's skills,
코너와 같은
기술을 가진 사람은
be valuable to those guys
in the worst way.
그들에 의해
악용을 당했겠구만.
특히 그에게는
약을 투여해
KENSI: Especially if he's
pumped up with drugs
that make it easier to
control and manipulate him.
조정하기 쉽도록
만든거로군요.
스코폴라민 이라는건데,
침대 밑에서 찾은
That would be scopolamine.
Lab results came back
from the pills you found
under the mattress.
그 약을 분석한
결과에요.
심문용 진정제군.
Interrogation med.
"좀비 마약"으로도
알려져 있습니다.
NELL: It's also known as
the "zombie drug".
이 약을 충분히 투여하면
상대를 완전히
장악할 수 있습니다.
Feed enough of it to someone
and you own them.
Well, Takahamo wasn't lying.
타카하모가
거짓말 한건 아니에.
기거리에서 팔리는
약이 아니야.
There's no street market
for that.
아까 그
부랑자가 알려준
ERIC: Now, we tracked the
car Connor got into
부분적인 차 번호와
차량 정보로
from the description
and the partial plate
코너가 타고간 차를
추적해 봤습니다.
the homeless man gave you.
차 소유자는
뱀지 파텔 입니다.
NELL: It's registered
to a Vamsi Patel.
"렛츠 크루즈" 차량 서비스 회사
소속 운전수 입니다.
He's a driver for the
"Let's Cruise" car service.
분명 그는 돈을 내고
차량 서비스를 받은게 아니죠.
Oddly enough, Connor's pickup
wasn't on the company manifest.
그런데...
But...
코너를 태우기
한시간 전에
Mark Simmons' pickup was,
마크 시몬스를
먼저 태웠습니다.
just an hour before
Connor was picked up.
문제는, 다음 장소는
어디일까 이겠군.
So the question is:
where's the next pickup?
확인해 볼께요...
Checking...
파텔씨?
KENSI:
Mr. Patel.
Bambi!
밤비!
뭐라구요?
What?
당신은
DJ Kimchi 겠군요.
And you must be DJ Kimchee.
I got your text, man.
문자 받았습니다.
I've heard your mixes,
I'm a huge fan.
당신의 믹싱을 들어봤어요.
정말 팬입니다.
여기 함 보세요.
All right, check this out:
끝내주는
총각파티가 될겁니다.
Your bachelor party
is going to crush.
Wow!
Spider Woman theme.
스파이더 우먼
의상이에요.
훌륭하죠.
Brilliant.
난 스트리퍼가
아니에요.
I'm not a stripper, man.
Oh, no, no, no.
노노노노, 물론 아니죠.
지금은 2015년 입니다.
Of course not. It's 2015.
알흠다운 당신은
흉내만 내시는거구요
You, beautiful lady,
are a burlesque entertainer.
나머진 제게 맏기세요,
제가 여자가 되는겁니다.
Empowerment, sister.
I am woman,
내 괴성을 들어봐요,
비욘세가 하는 말은 모두...
hear me roar,
everything Beyonc챕 talked--
Okay, not a problem.
네, 그것도 문제 없어요.
좀 섹시한 경찰 컨셉을 원하시면
You want to go with a little
sexy cop kind of thing,
그것도 할 수 있습니다.
I can work with that.
오케이, 좋아요.
I think I just have to go with...
Okay, listen, I need you
진정제라도 확 먹일까부다.
to take a chill pill,
all right?
한 10알 쯤 먹여줄까?
Why don't you just take,
like, ten chill pills?
우린 진짜
연방요원입니다.
We're actual
Federal agents.
진짜루요?
Wait, for reals?
진짜진짜루.
Oh, for reals, reals.
내 차를 위장잠입용으로
쓰시려는 건가요?
You want to hire my ride
for undercover?
경찰들 한테는
할인율이 아마...
Law enforcement
discount may be
꽤 높을...
quite a lot...
Ehp, ehp, ehp...
왜요?
What?
당신 전문분야는
아니겠지만,
We realize this is
out of your territory,
but we really need you listen
right now.
지금부턴 우리 말을
잘 들어야 합니다.
당신은 어제 병원에서
누군가를 태웠어요.
You made a pickup
yesterday at the VA.
An unauthorized pickup.
무단 영업이죠.
무단이요?
Unauthorized?
전, 나중에 기록하려고...
No, I was going to put down...
Uhp, uhp, uhp, uhp, uhp...!
그 전엔
마크 시몬스를 태웠구요.
Prior to that,
you picked up Mark Simmons.
그건
예약된거 였죠.
That was on the books.
질문이
두개 있습니다.
Two questions:
첫째, 그 둘은
연관이 있나요?
First, are those two connected?
이제 말해도 돼요...
간략하게.
Now you can speak... briefly.
Okay, uh...
시몬스가 자기
친구를 태워 달라고
100불을 지불했습니다.
Simmons paid me 100 bucks
to get his friend.
He said this guy
did not have an account.
그 친구는 은행 계정이
없다고 했습니다.
두번째 질문:
그를 어디로 데려다 줬죠?
Second question:
where'd you take him?
Uh, the Valley.
밸리입니다.
챈들러와 콜팩스 교차로.
Uh, Chandler and Colfax.
바로 거긴 PFA 본부가
있는 곳이야.
That's where the Protectors
of a Free America
headquarters are located.
캘런한테 전화할께.
I'm gonna call Callen.
Look.
Ooh, look at this!
- 함 봐요.
- 와, 죽이는데?
그게 맘에 들어요?
You like that?
[ 얼간이의 열정 ]
색 좋네.
It's a good color.
How much?
얼마죠?
당신한텐...
Well, for you, uh,
15% 착한경찰 할인을
해드릴게요.
15% good cop discount.
됐나요?
Okay?
- 뭔일이야?
- 들었잖아.
What is happening?
DEEKS: You heard the man.
I get a 15% off...
15% 깍아 준대.
BOTH:
...good cop discount.
착한경찰 할인.
이건 빈티지 아이템이야.
DEEKS: This thing is vintage.
You can't find these online.
온라인에서 안팔아.
누가 이걸 좋아할지 알아?
You know who's
gonna love it?
My little brother.
내 맨티 동생.
뭘 도와드릴까요, 여러분?
What can I do you for, fellas?
코너 러트넘.
Connor Rutnam.
MAN: Afraid I don't know
그가 누군지 모르겠군요.
who that is.
CALLEN: What about Mark Simmons?
마크 시몬스는요?
Ah, you just
missed him.
방금 갔습니다.
Mm-hmm.
Just missed him.
방금 갔다...
어디로 갔나요?
Where'd he go?
Well, let's see...
글쎄요... 아마
라티노 간부회의에 갔을겁니다.
I think it was
the Latino Caucus.
아, 그게 아니지,
내 정신 좀 봐.
Ah, hell,
what am I thinking?
오늘은 목요일이니
Today's Thursday--
he volunteers
게이와 레즈비언 센터에
봉사하러 갔겠네요.
at the Gay and
Lesbian Center.
오, 저녁식사전에
증오범죄나 몇개 저지르려구요?
Oh, he's just getting in a few
hate crimes before dinner?
그들이 뭐라는지 아세요?
Well, you know what they say:
누군가의 증오범죄는
다른 누군가의 정의이다.
one man's hate crime
is another man's justice.
Is that what they say?
그들이 그랬다구요?
경찰 뱃지가 있다고해서
백인으로 봐 주지는 않습니다.
You think that badge puts
a white hat on your heads?
우리가 보기엔
You're as much the enemy
당신은 알카에다와
별반 다를게 없는 적입니다.
as Al Qaeda,
far as we're concerned.
당신의 '적'이 훈장받은
전쟁 영웅을 구하려고 합니다.
Your "enemy" is trying to save
a decorated war veteran.
당신같은 싸가지를
SAM: Or do you
consider a Marine
구해주려고 하는 해병도
적이라 생각하나요?
who tries to save your sorry ass
the enemy, too?
MAN: It's been real nice
chattin' with you.
대화 즐거웠습니다.
당신네 겁없는 지도자
프레드 킹톤은 어디있나요?
Where's your fearless leader,
Fred Kington?
Not here.
여기 없습니다.
그가 열심히 일하는
이민자들의
Is he helping some
hardworking immigrants
영주권 신청서 작성을
도와주고 있나요?
fill out their green card
applications?
엄밀히 말하면,
That would be
illegal immigrants,
'불법' 이민자들이죠.
technically speaking.
이슬람교는 21세기의
잘못된 종교입니다!
Islam is the false religion
of the 21st century!
이슬람은
빈곤을 유발합니다!
Islam causes poverty!
Islam pollutes
the honor of women!
이슬람은
여성의 명예를 더럽힙니다!
생명을 파괴합니다!
Islam destroys lives!
이슬람은 가버려라!
Islam has got to go!
(gunshot)
(people screaming)
연방요원입니다!
Federal agents!
연방요원입니다.
Federal agent.
OFFICER: LAPD!
We got shots fired...
(people shouting in panic)
We need immediate backup!
Repeat: immediate backup!
길 건너에서 쏜거야.
Shot came from
across the street.
저격수가 쏜거군.
SAM:
It's a sniper shot.
지붕이닷!
The roof!
CALLEN:
Good.
좋아.
연방요원이다!
Federal agent!
프레드 킹톤을 연행해서
본부로 데려가는 중입니다.
Fred Kington's in custody,
on his way to the boatshed.
DEEKS:
Guys in the SUV?
SUV에 있던 놈들은?
Didn't get a look
at their faces.
얼굴을 못 봤는데.
그들 조직 구조로 봐서
그중에 한명은
And from their builds,
it's possible one of them
코너였을
가능성이 있어.
could have been Connor.
차 서비스 회사
운전수 한테서는
SAM:
Driver from the car service
뭐 알아낸거 없어?
give you anything?
코너가 최종 목적지에 대해선
한마디도 안했답니다.
He said Connor didn't say
a word the whole trip.
의식을
잃었다는데요?
Seemed zoned out.
That's the scopolamine.
스코폴라민
때문이겠군.
KENSI:
Yeah.
저격수가 여기
올라왔었네요.
The shooter was up here,
all right.
저쪽 난간에
먼지가
See that disturbance in the dust
흐트러진
자국이 있죠?
right there, on the ledge?
그건 저격수의
팔꿈치 자국일꺼고
That would have been
the shooter's elbow.
여기 이쪽에도
자국 두개가 있는데
Right here, these two marks--
이건 저격수 디딤 발이겠고
that would have been
his front foot
두번째 이 자국은
무릎자국 일겁니다.
and the second mark
would've been his knee.
그 얘긴, 저격수가
왼손잡이라는 얘깁니다.
Which means the shooter's
left-handed.
본부에서 본 사진속엔
In the photos
we saw in Ops,
코너가 오른손잡이었어.
Connor was shooting
right-handed.
Exactly.
맞아요.
So who took the shot?
그럼 도대체
누가 쏜거지?
And why do they need Connor?
그리고 코너는
왜 필요했을까?
킹톤씨.
Mr. Kington.
분명히 말씀드리는데,
For the record,
우리 그룹은 여기 미국내에서
무슬림들을 죽이자고
주창하지 않습니다.
my group does not advocate
killing Muslims here in America,
unless, of course,
they are confirmed terrorists.
만일 그런놈들이 있다면
그건 명백한 테러범들입니다.
하지만 분명히,
Well, just for the record,
당신네 선언서엔
your manifesto proposes
미국땅에있는 모든 무슬림들을
뿌리뽑아야 한다고 되 있더군요.
the eradication of all
Muslim presence on U.S. soil.
예, 그들을 모두
그들 나라로 추방해서
Yes, by deporting them
back to their homelands
거기서 그들 모두가 원하는
이슬람 율법대로 살라고 하고
where they can practice
Sharia law all they want
우린 제발 좀
건드리지 말란 얘기죠.
and leave us in peace.
99.9% of them
do leave us in peace.
그들의 99.9%는
우릴 건드리지 않습니다.
계속 그런식으로
얘기할건가요?
You keep telling yourself that,
당신은 알라의 이름으로
저질러진
you're gonna be responsible
for every tragedy
모든 비극에 대해
책임을 져야 할겁니다.
that comes down
in the name of Allah.
토마스 제퍼슨
스스로도
You know,
Thomas Jefferson himself
preached a policy
of isolationism.
고립주의 정책을
역설했었죠.
우린 지금 오지랖이
너무 넓은거요.
We keep sticking our nose
in everybody else's business,
그게 이사건의
실체입니다.
this is what happens.
당신은 당신의
국외 추방 정책을
CALLEN: But since you can't
force the government
to adopt your deportation plan,
정부에
강요할 수는 없으니
몇명을 본보기로
why not pop a few
그들 예배당에서
쫓아 내보지 그랬어요?
outside their places
of worship, huh?
그들에게
미국으로 이민오는게
Give them the idea
that maybe moving here
결코 좋은 생각이 아니라는
생각이 들게끔 해주는거죠.
wasn't such a great idea.
Mm-hmm.
그리고 어째서 내가
우리의 항의집회 장소에서
And why would I have
someone assassinated
누가 암살당하길
바라겠습니까?
at the very place
we're protesting?
아주 확실한
알리바이군요.
It's a hell of an alibi.
당신은 지상에서
CALLEN:
You, on the ground
점잔이나 떨고있고...
당신의 추종자들이
with your hands clean...
minions doing
옥상에서 대신
더러운 일을 하고있는거지.
your dirty work
from a rooftop.
당신의 항의집회 군중속에
마크 시몬스가 없더군요.
I didn't see Mark Simmons
on your protest line.
마크 시몬스를
몇일동안 못 봤습니다.
I haven't seen
Mark Simmons in days.
하지만 한가지는 알죠:
But I do know one thing:
그는 진정한
애국잡니다.
he's a true patriot.
당신의 "진정한 애국자"가
Well, your "true patriot"
is messing up
스코폴라민으로 코너 러트넘의
머리속을 뒤집어 놨소.
Connor Rutnam's head
with scopolamine.
그가 누구 얘기든
쉽게 동요될 수 있도록.
Making him susceptible
to someone's influence.
Say, the leader of
an extremist group
극단주의 그룹의 리더가
명령만 하면 언제든
그의 저격술을
죄없는 무슬림들을
that could use
his sniper skills
to kill innocent Muslims.
죽이는데
쓸 수 있도록.
I've never heard of
Connor Rutnam.
코너 러트넘 이라고는
들어본적도 없소.
한가지 덧붙이자면...
And by the way,
세상에 "죄없는 무슬림"이란 없소.
there's no such thing
as an "innocent" Muslim.
마크 시몬스가
왼손잡이로 확인 됐습니다.
We confirmed Mark Simmons
is left-handed.
저격수 교육을
Though he doesn't have
any sniper training,
받지 않았음에도
불구하고
he did earn a marksman
qualification
그는 군복무중
저격병 자격을 얻었습니다.
during his time
in the Army.
주소는 알아냈나?
We got an address?
네, 하지만 그는
거기 없을거에요.
We do, but I don't think
you'll find him there.
시몬스의 기록들을
주워 모아 보니
From what we gleaned
from his records,
그는 PFA에서
밴을 운전하더군요.
Simmons drives a PFA van.
오늘 그가 시내 6가 길에 있는
이 주차장에 주차해 있는 장면이
The traffic camera shows him
pulling into this parking lot
교통 카메라에
잡혔습니다.
on 6th Street,
downtown today.
그는 아직
거기 있습니다.
He's still there.
주차장에
들어간 시간은?
What time did he enter the lot?
한시간 전이요.
An hour ago.
DEEKS: That gives him plenty of time
회교사원으로 가서 총을 쏘고
저기 내려와 있을
충분한 시간이네.
to take the shot at the mosque
and get down there.
캘런과 샘에게
전화하겠습니다.
I'll call Callen and Sam.
DEEKS: Good work.
NELL: Thanks.
- 잘했어.
- 감솨요.
밴이 보여.
We got eyes on the van.
네.
KENSI (over radio):
All right.
우리도 보입니다.
DEEKS (over radio):
Now so do we.
- 저기있는 흰색 차야.
- 넵, 알씀다.
CALLEN: It's the white one, right there.
KENSI: Yep, got it.
시몬스 낌새가
있었나요?
DEEKS:
Any sign of Simmons?
아직.
Not yet.
여기 좀더 있을거면
DEEKS: Listen, if we're gonna
be here a while,
근처에 끝내주는
타코 파는데가 있는데.
there's a great little taco
stand around the corner.
SAM: It's a stakeout,
not a picnic, Deeks.
이건 잠복근무지
소풍이 아니라구, 딕스.
DAD:
Come on, guys...
이리와, 얘들아.
우리 그냥 7/11 가서
사 먹으면 안돼?
BOY: Can we just go by 7-Eleven
and get some? - No!
귀여운 식구들이군.
Look at that cute
little family.
- 로리와 스티브도 올건가?
- 하지마
So, are Lori and Steve gonna be there?
Stop it.
엄마 얘 좀 못하게 해 줘
Mom, make him stop.
BOY (mimicking):
부모가 왜
아무것도 안하지?
Why aren't the parents
doing something?
안하긴 왜 안해?
애들을 '무시'하고 있잖아.
They are doing something--
they're ignoring them.
가끔은 그냥
내버려둬야 한다구.
You know, sometimes you
got to roll with it.
누나가 때렸어
She hit me, Mom!
쟤들 서로 막 때리는데?
Th-They're hitting each other.
애들을 너무 놔서
기르는 것 같이보여.
Seems like pretty lax
parenting to me.
- 난 모르겠네.
- 내 생각 을 말해볼까?
I'm not here to judge.
SAM: I have a theory.
네, 해보세요.
Oh, yeah? Let's hear it.
그게 '기진맥진 방법'
이라는거야.
It's called exhaustion.
Mm-hmm.
그거 확실한 건가?
CALLEN: You so
sure about that?
물론이지.
SAM: Yeah, I'm
so sure about that.
자네들도 모두
몇년 있다가
I'll tell you what,
we'll revisit the subject
각자 애들이 생기면
그때 다시 얘기해 줄께.
in a few years when all of you
have a couple of kids each.
Mm-hmm.
그때까지 애들을
입양 안보내고
데리고 산다면 말이지.
That's if you haven't put them
up for adoption already.
(chuckles)
나타났어요.
KENSI:
Head's up, guys.
시몬스가 와요.
Simmons is
on the move.
Mark Simmons...
마크 시몬스?
Federal agents.
연방 요원입니다.
KENSI:
Stop!
서랏!
쓰레기통 뒤에
그리 오래 숨어있지 않았어.
CALLEN: Didn't take cover
behind the Dumpster very long.
그냥 튀어나와서
총을 쐈지.
He just came out firing.
마치 우리보고
쏴달라고 한것 같네.
Like he wanted us
to shoot him.
- 경찰을 이용한 자살인가?
- 그럴거면 쓰레기통 뒤엔 왜 숨었지?
Suicide by cop?
Why hide behind the Dumpster at all?
어쩌면 우리 중 한명을
제거하기 위한
DEEKS: Maybe he was hoping
it would buy him enough time
시간을 벌어보려고
한걸지도 모르죠.
to pick one of us off.
Then he would have fired
from behind the Dumpster.
그렇담 쓰레기통 뒤에서
총을 쐈었어야지.
Doesn't make
any sense.
말이 완돼.
지갑엔 열쇠하고
현금 조금 밖에 없어요.
Got a wallet, keys,
a little cash.
- 휴대폰은 없어?
- 없어요.
No cell phone?
No.
시몬스가 카림 무바와
통화한 기록이 있습니다.
ERIC: Simmons' call history
connects him to a Karim Mubar,
여기 LA에서 잘 알려진
알카에다 지지자죠.
a known Al-Qaeda sympathizer
here in Los Angeles.
PFA 정회원이
알카에다 첩자와
What is a card-carrying member
of the PFA doing
무슨 일을 벌이고
있었던 걸까?
with an operative
from Al-Qaeda?
여기 도움 될만한게
있어요.
Well, we have something
that might help.
회교사원 총격장면
CCTV 영상입니다.
Security cam footage
of the mosque shooting.
총 맞기 직전의
저 젊은이를 주시해 보세요.
Keep an eye on the young man
just before he's shot.
무슨 말을 했군.
He said something.
Play that back slowly.
천천히 다시 돌려 봐.
이제 줌인 해봐.
Now zoom in.
(no voice)
Kens?
켄지?
"Allahu Akbar."
"알라후 악바르"
"신은 위대하다"라는
뜻입니다.
Means "God is great."
아름다운 문장이죠.
It's a beautiful phrase.
대부분의 자살 폭파범은
자살전에 저 말을 하지.
Most suicide bombers say it
before they blow themselves up.
그는 시몬스가 자길
죽일거라는 걸 알았군요.
He knew Simmons was
gonna kill him.
왜죠?
Why?
PFA가 무고한 무슬림들을
죽이는 것처럼 보이게 한것 같아.
My guess is to make it look like
PFA is killing innocent Muslims,
반미국 정서를
자극하는거지.
stir up anti-American sentiment.
시몬스는
알카에다를 위해 일했어.
Simmons was working
with Al-Qaeda.
그를 이용해 코너에게 접근해서
그에게 약을 준거야.
They used him to get to Connor,
feed him the meds.
PFA 회원가입은
계략이었군.
So the PFA membership
was a ruse.
그와 연락한 사람들을 추적했을때
PFA로 유도 되도록 했구만.
Anybody got onto him,
the trail leads back to the PFA.
시몬스와 젊은 무슬림
이 둘은
DEEKS: So both Simmons
and the young Muslim
나름 정당한 이유로
희생을 한거네요.
sacrificed themselves
for the cause.
불행히도 러트넘은 아직
알카에다의 영향력 아래 있다네.
Unfortunately, that still leaves
Mr. Rutnam in Al-Qaeda's sway.
뭔가 큰 것을 위해서
그를 꼭 구해야 겠군.
Must be saving him
for something big.
Maybe a high-ranking member
of the Muslim community?
무슬림 단체의
고위직 회원 같은거요?
시몬스와 무바르가 최근에
같은 장소에 있었다는
Do we have anything
that puts Simmons and Mubar
무슨 증거 같은건 없나?
in a common location
recently?
네, 신용카드
기록을 보니, 그들은
Yes, credit card
records put them
지난 2주 동안 6번이나
시내 한 카페에
함께 있었습니다.
at a cafe downtown half a dozen
times in the past couple weeks.
카페 근처에
회교 사원은 없나?
Any mosques
near that cafe?
없습니다.
No,
하지만 칸타라 문화센터가
2블럭 서쪽에 있습니다.
but the Cantara Cultural Center
is just two blocks west.
아마르 핫산이
오늘 늦게
And Amare Hassan
is scheduled
한 종교모임에서
연설을 하기로
되어있습니다.
to speak at a religious unity
conference later today.
핫산은 매우 존경받는
회교 시아파
성직자야.
Hassan is a very well-respected
and popular Mullah.
He speaks out
against extremists.
극단주의자들을
배척하자고
설교를 하지.
그를 암살하면
이슬람 교계에
엄청난 화를
His assassination would light
a huge fire
in the Islamic community.
불러오게 될거야.
It's a perfect target.
완벽한 목표네요.
그런 모임은
경비가 아주 허술하지.
Event like that is gonna have
some serious security.
Which makes Connor Rutnam
the perfect assassin.
코너 러트넘이 아주
완벽한 암살자가 되겠군요.
PILOT: Eagle One on site,
beginning rooftop search.
이글-1 현장 도착.
지붕 검색을 시작한다.
알았다 이글-1.
CONTROL: Copy, Eagle One.
켄지, 딕스,
제자리에 위치했나?
Kensi, Deeks,
you in position?
방금 완료했습니다.
Just got set up.
저는 연단이 보이는
위치에 있습니다.
DEEKS:
I got the podium in my sights.
코너가 저기 어디 있다면
그도 연단이 보이는
위치에 있다는 얘기죠.
Which means if Connor's
out there, he does, too.
헤티, 이벤트 주최측과
얘기해 보셨나요?
Hetty, have you been in touch
with the event coordinators?
해봤지. 그런데 핫산씨가
그의 연설을 취소하길
Yes, and unfortunately
Mr. Hassan refuses
거부하고 있다네.
to cancel his address.
그럴경우 비겁한 행위의
선례가 되는걸 우려하는 거지.
He feels it would signal
an act of cowardice.
그럼 이제 우리한테
달린거란 얘기군요.
And that means it's on us.
딕스!
Deeks!
주변 건물 옥상에서
뭐라도 발견했나?
Anything
on the surrounding rooftops?
암껏두 아직 없습니다.
I got nothing, yet.
코너의 사정거리는
멀리있는 건물 몇개는
Connor's field of fire has
a number of distant buildings
훌쩍 넘어.
he can make the shot from.
그 조준경으론
잘 보이나, 켄지?
How you doing behind
that scope, Kensi?
넵.
I'm good.
알겠다.
잘 보인답니다.
DEEKS:
Copy that, she's good.
이글-1, 뭐 없나?
Eagle One, anything?
없습니다, 오버.
PILOT:
Negative contact.
Over.
멀리있는 건물들을
모두 눈으로 확인 했습니다.
We've got our eyes on every
distant building out there.
어쩌면 그게
아닐지도 몰라.
Maybe that's the problem.
이 일을 꾸민 사람은
그의 장거리 저격수가
Whoever set this up wanted
the insurance
발견되지 않을
확실한 대책이 필요했을꺼야.
that his long-distance sniper
didn't be spotted.
그를 가까운 건물안에
있게 하는거지.
Put him in a closer building.
맞아.
Yep.
이글-1,
변경사항이 있다.
GRANGER (over radio): Eagle One,
let's change it up.
근접지역 수색을
시작하라.
Begin checking
the immediate area.
알았습니다.
PILOT:
Copy that.
움직임을 발견했어.
I got movement.
블라이 요원,
상황보고 하라.
GRANGER: Sitrep, Agent Blye.
코너와 다른 두명이
1시 방향 거적 안에 있습니다.
I got Connor plus two,
under the tarp at one o'clock.
나도 보여.
I got 'em.
위치가 어디지?
What's the location?
켄지의 조준경 데이터를 근거로
거리와 방향을 산출해 보면...
Uh, distance and bearing from
Kensi's scope data puts us at...
웨스트 올림픽가 605번지
북동쪽 코너입니다.
605 West Olympic Boulevard,
northeast corner.
한 블럭 거리네.
We're one block out.
블라이 요원.
GRANGER:
Agent Blye,
코너가 조준에 잡히면
바로 사살하게.
if Connor lines up a shot,
you take him out.
KENSI:
Copy that.
알겠습니다.
(tires screech)
켄지, 우리가 도착했어.
Kensi, we're here.
코너가 아직
그 자리에 있나?
Connor in position, yet?
거의...
Almost...
켄지,
GRANGER: Kensi,
우린 위험을
감수할 수 없네.
we can't take any chances.
Kens.
켄지.
기다려!
우리가 거의 다 왔어.
Hold off!
We're almost there!
켄지, 괜찮아?
Kens, you good?
괜찮아.
I'm fine.
블라이 요원,
또 다른 기회는 없을거네.
GRANGER: Agent Blye, you're not
gonna get another opportunity.
그의 잘못이 아닙니다!
저희에게 기회를 주세요!
This isn't his fault!
Just give us a chance!
우린 그를
저지 해야만 해.
GRANGER:
We have to stop him.
샘과 캘런이
옥상에 도착했다.
All right, Sam and Callen
are on the roof.
Take the shot, Agent Blye.
총을 쏘게,
블라이 요원.
켄지, 지금 쏴.
Kensi, take the shot now.
샘, 미안해요.
Sam, I'm sorry.
연방요원이다!
Federal agents!
계속 해!
Get back!
꼼짝마, 상사.
Stay down, Gunny.
끝내주는 솜씨였어,
파트너.
That's a hell of
a shot, partner.
(gasping quietly)
Yeah.
손 머리 위로.
Hands on your head.
움직이지마, 상사.
Okay, don't move, Gunny.
일어서.
Get up. Get up.
Get up.
좋아.
All right.
가만있어, 상사.
Stay still, Gunny.
좋아, 손 이리 내.
Okay, give me your hand.
괜찮을거야, 알겠지?
It's gonna be okay,
all right?
괜찮을거라구.
It's gonna be okay.
방금 해나군이
러트넘씨를 안전하게
HETTY:
I just got word
퇴역군인 병원으로
되돌려 보냈다는
that Mr. Hanna has safely
returned Mr. Rutnam
전갈을 받았네.
to the VA hospital.
그의 아내와 딸이
곧 그리로 갈걸세.
His wife and daughter are going
to join him shortly.
그거 아주 잘됐네요.
Well, that is great.
SAM:
Ah...
남편분은 저기
바깥에 있습니다.
He's out there.
당신을
기다리고 있습니다.
He's waiting for you.
Thank you so much.
정말 고마워요.
(computer chimes)
오, 멘토링 사이트에서
메시지가 왔네.
Oh, I got a message
from the mentoring site.
곧 있을 내
첫 만남을 생각하니 난...
I cannot wait to have
my first meeting with...
바이런?!
...Byron?!
"친애하는 딕스씨,"
CALLEN:
"Dear Mr. Deeks.
"스케쥴이
중복되는 바람에"
"Due to
a scheduling conflict,
"we've reassigned your case.
"담당하실 학생이
바뀌게 되었습니다."
"선생님의
새 동생은..."
Your new Little Brother is..."
"바이런 체스터 입니다".
"Byron... Chester""
"바이런의
관심분야는,"
KENSI:
"Byron's interests include
"3차원 체스"
"three-dimensional chess,
"응용수학,
그리고..."
advanced calculus
and..." (laughs)
"독일 오페라..."
"German opera""
N-No, German...
피쉬 타코하고
서핑은 어떻게 된거지?
Uh, what happened to-to
fish tacos and-and surfing
얼간이 삼총사하고
그 걸래 머리는...?
and the Three Stooges and the
floppy hair that this is...?
- 딕스군.
- 네.
Mr. Deeks.
Yeah.
This is gonna be good practice.
이건 좋은
연습이 될거야.
자네는 자식이 생기면
어떨거라는 예상은
You can have all the
expectations you want
맘대로 할 수 있겠지만
when you have children,
but you can never predict
실제 당해보지 않고는
어떤 결과가 나올지
절대로 예측하지 못할거네.
who you're going
to end up with.
내 생각에,
바이런도 괜찮은것 같아.
CALLEN: I think
Byron's gonna be great.
Plus you never know
when a working knowledge
혹시알아?
'마법의 피리'
of The Magic Flute is gonna
come in handy.
부는 방법이
도움이 될지?
그거 독일 오페라에
나오는 거잖아요.
That's a German
opera reference.
I don't get that
전 그거 몰라요.
저는 독일 오페라는
모르거든요.
because I don't
know a German opera.
잘 해보게, 딕스군.
Bravo, Mr. Deeks.
잘 해봐.
Bravo.
잘 해보라구.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man